<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Joseph M. Sleiman -- Index on jmsleiman.com</title><link>https://jmsleiman.com/</link><description>Recent content in Joseph M. Sleiman -- Index on jmsleiman.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jmsleiman.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>D&amp;D 5e Character Journal Project</title><link>https://jmsleiman.com/blog/2024/05/28-dd-5e-character-journal-project/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jmsleiman.com/blog/2024/05/28-dd-5e-character-journal-project/</guid><description>Why Revamp the Character Sheet Anyway? Because the default 5e character sheet kind of sucks, in my opinion. For new players, there is way too much noise - there are loads of things they won&amp;rsquo;t ever use, and plenty of space devoted to details that players never consult, and so little to what is frequently checked. For experienced players, there is still too much noise, and they have to create all sorts of hacks to write down everything going on.</description></item><item><title>Pandemic Project: Outdoor Sink</title><link>https://jmsleiman.com/blog/2020/07/01-pandemic-project-outdoor-sink/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jmsleiman.com/blog/2020/07/01-pandemic-project-outdoor-sink/</guid><description>Installing an Outdoor Sink Final Result Tada! We use the little baskets for storing cutlery, and the counter is used for prep before using the grill. The bucket catches the water, but you could use a drain pipe.
Outdoor sink installed Initial Idea With the pandemic in full swing, and my parents still wanting us to come by for outdoor dinners (as is permitted for us here in Ontario), I realized a really practical tool would be an outdoor sink.</description></item><item><title>Improvements to jwt-go</title><link>https://jmsleiman.com/blog/2020/05/15-improvements-to-jwt-go/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jmsleiman.com/blog/2020/05/15-improvements-to-jwt-go/</guid><description>Improving jwt-go Brief run-down of jwt A relatively new technology, jwt are json web t&amp;gt;okens. They are represented as a text string, three parts separated by dots. The three parts are base64-encoded JSON objects that can be decoded and then re-constructed as JSON objects.
Their structure is what makes them special, and it&amp;rsquo;s well-defined in a &amp;gt;RFC7519, and I won&amp;rsquo;t go too far into detail, but essentially we have the header, the body, and the signature.</description></item><item><title>Hypercube Election</title><link>https://jmsleiman.com/blog/2015/12/08-hypercube-election/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jmsleiman.com/blog/2015/12/08-hypercube-election/</guid><description>Simulation of a Leader Election in an n-HyperCube Demo Shiny stuff first!
Run Stage 0
Context I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on this for quite some time, but never had the patience to actually finish it. However, now it&amp;rsquo;s complete. You can find it on GitHub. It&amp;rsquo;s written in python 2 and has few dependencies.
Leader Elections Leader elections are usually applied to distributed systems. A herd of computers on a network are trying to determine who to put in charge, organically and without outside knowledge.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://jmsleiman.com/storage/wip/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jmsleiman.com/storage/wip/</guid><description>Outline when to use cabinets:
when to use drawers:
sizes of drawers when to use shelves:
when to use chests:
what to put in chest runners: what to put in bins/boxes:</description></item></channel></rss>